Hello everyone, so we've already
learned about some concepts
related to streams, right?
Today in this video, I'll guide
you through a
simple example of
data reading and writing in Java.
More specifically, today we'll
create another chapter. Let's
open our project. Inside, we
'll add
a `new` and a
package, which we'll name `chapter10`. This is
our 10th chapter.
Inside this, we'll
add a new class, which we
'll name `video59`.
And first, as always, we'll use the same
principle. We'll create
a `main` function. Inside
this `main` function, we'll add a `
systemout` statement, for example.
After running `video59`, the first thing
we'll do is... You can see that...
The video
59 is playing now. Next, we'll
click on
the "
by stream" section in this document. As I explained
in the previous video, the
difference between "by stream" and "
character" is that
you only read the characters. Please note that
for languages ​​with
accents or hieroglyphs,
you should use "character
stream." This allows for a
wider data range,
similar to using "
in" or "long" characters.
If you have a lot of data,
you can use "
character." As for "
buffer," if your computer
has a lot of memory resources (like C, for
example) and you want it to be faster, you
can use "buffer." The
idea behind it is
similar, just that the
method is slightly different.
Thanh Nga said that today I will give an
example with a simple...  The simplest part is
this `by stream` section. First,
you can look at this part.
Actually, I'll just copy
this part exactly from
our lesson plan. I've
already included the sample code, but I'll
use this for speed. Inside
the `mail` function, you'll copy it.
Here, I'll copy this part
and paste it in. Instead of
running video 59, I'll delete it and
paste it in. So, first,
we have this file. And
here, you can see that we
need to import these. Here,
we'll import the `stream` file
from `java.io`. Similarly,
we'll import the `outstream` file
from `java.io`. We have
this file. I don't know
what the error is; it says we need to
throw an exception, right? So,
right here, I'll add an
exception.
For this file, what does it throw?
We click on `throw`.  The so-called IO
exception is like this: it
includes all possible exceptions.
It's replaced by this: this
is our code.
If you code like this, do
you think
it will run? Personally, I do
n't think it will.
I'll explain the meaning
of the sheet we just copied. In
reality,
we're creating two objects: one is
output and the other is input.
Our input is the data read from
this text file, and our output
is this file. The idea behind
this code block is that
we read data from this file.
You see, we're
looping. We're looping line by line, character by character. That is,
we're writing the output from this input file.
We're copying data from one file
to another. It's just that the
filenames are different.
First, we have
this data, and if we
run it... Guess what? It won't work.
Personally, I don't think it will
because these files do
n't exist on our computer.
Now you'll see an
exception pop up. Let's try
running it again. Immediately,
we get an exception. It says "
exception in thread m".
Our exception is called "file not file".
Notice that it displays
the text "sanad chtech" - the
system cannot find the file specific.
This proves that
this file doesn't exist on
our system. Now we
start scratching our heads wondering why this file does
n't exist, because in reality,
this file isn't on our computer, right? So, the
error is here. First,
you'll create...  Right here, in the folder,
right outside this question,
guys, right here, you
'll right-click and select "New".
Here, we'll create
a new text file.
You'll click here. Inside,
this thing is... well, this is weird, is
n't it? I'll just type something random, guys. I
'll type something like this... then I'll
save it. After I
press Ctrl+S, immediately
click on the question folder to
save it here. I'll name it, for example, "
test". Okay, I'll name
it "input" for clarity.
I'll name it "input".
Click OK. So now,
inside our
Genit project, we have an input file.
And if we double-click
here, you'll see that this
is our data. Don't type accented
characters, guys, for safety,
type without accents.  I see
that I've added a fake data
like this, and after I changed it like
that, I'll replace this "x" with "x".
Please note that when
you use the input stream file,
you don't need the prefix "
dot tex" like this. It will understand automatically
because you usually
only read text. You see
that we pass in a name,
we pass in a string
name. So here, I'll give it
an input. I'll call it input
like this. This time, I'll press the
save button. I'll run it again. You'll
see that after I run it again, there
are no errors. But we
don't know if
we succeeded or not,
so now, I'll right-click
here and refresh.
You'll see that we have a refresh button.
Immediately, we have a new file
called AAG txt. And if
I click on it...  Do you see
anything? The content of
this input file is exactly the same as the file
called "out Again," and now I'll
call it "review in file." Okay, I'll find the
part where I'll open this file. You
'll see there's a problem.
So, our file is wrong. Our file
doesn't
have the prefix '.txt'. So it's wrong,
while the "out Again" file is
okay. This time, I'll add it.
I'll rename it. I'll
reflect on it. It
seems we need to
add the prefix 'txt'. Okay,
this time I'll try deleting the "out
Again" file. Also, inside
this... if you run "finally,"
after we close the print part...
after you read it, I'll add
a final line: "system out," "
system out," and I'll add the
word "and." That's it. I'll...  Let's put
it like this. Now, let's
run it again, guys. You can
see that after renaming it, it
seems
we need the prefix '
txt' for it to run correctly. Let's
run it again. So, we
have the word 'end'.
Now, let's refresh it.
We have the word 'out'. And if we
call it 'show file', you'll
see that the file prefix
this time is called 'text document'. This
proves that we have
successfully read and written, right?
This is the simplest way
for you to read a file. In
fact, the process of
reading a file involves calling
Java classes and then
manipulating the
functions. It's very
simple, right? However,
now let's make a small change.
Why did I leave the file name as 'txt'?
You can see that...
We've put our file outside.
Now, if
you see chapter 10 like
this, I'll drag it inside.
I'll drag and drop it
inside chapter 10. You see,
we have the input file, it's at the
same level as this one. I'll
delete the file again.
I'll delete the word "out Again," and now I'll
run it again. You see, immediately
we get a "file not file" error. The question is,
why? It's inside
chapter 10, it won't run,
while if I put it on the
outermost layer, it runs.
And now, if I change it like
this... I'll try this, I
don't know if it will work.
Personally, I do
n't know if typing it like this will
work. I'll
change it like this, and then I'll
run it again. Why do
I type it like this?  It's eating you guys again.
I typed it like this and it ate it again, it's very
unrealistic, right? Let's
refresh it, refresh this one. There
's a file out. Again, open it. That's right, a
question arises: what does
this text I passed in mean?
This is the concept of 'p' in
Java. In the next video, I will
guide you. We will
learn about Java classes and parts together,
okay?